Finding Aid for Ecology Center of Ann Arbor records, 1969-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical Files
  - 1985-2004, mainly 1990-2000
    - Pesticides
      - Ann Arbor pesticide policy, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
      - Ann Arbor pesticide resolution, 1986-1987 (Box 14)
      - Clippings and articles, 1988-1989 (Box 14)
      - Integrated Pest Management, 1990 (Box 14)
      - Pesticide Control (meeting with commercial applicators), 1989 (Box 14)
      - Pesticide Control Act (HB 4489), 1991 (Box 14)
      - Pesticide Incident Reporting System, 1988-1989; undated (Box 14)
      - Pesticide Management Task Force, 1985-1986 (Box 14)
      - Pesticide Ordinances, 1995-1998 (Box 14)
      - Pesticides Policy Statement, 1988 (Box 14)
      - Pesticide pre-emption, 1991-1993 (Box 14)
      - Pesticide Task Force, 1987-1988 (Box 14)
    - Pfizer addition, 2001 (Box 14)
    - Plastic bag recycling, 1988 (Box 14)
    - Plastic compost (HB 4730), 1997 (Box 14)
    - ReBicycle Project, 1996-1998 (Box 14)
    - Recombinant bovine growth hormone (rbGH), 1994 (Box 14)
    - Recycling / Reuse, 1994-1996 (Box 14)
    - Regional planning, 2001 (Box 14)
    - Stossel (John) and forum on challenges of genetically modified organisms, 2001 (Box 14)
    - Supermarkets and organic food, 1988-1989 (Box 14)
    - Sustainable Washtenaw, 1999-2001 (Box 15)
    - Tax Credit-Griffin Recycled Materials Tax Credit Bill, 1996 (Box 15)
    - Textile Road Superfund Site, 1997 (Box 15)
    - Toxics Reduction Project, 1991-1996 (Box 15)
    - Toxics Spill Rules, 1997 (Box 15)
    - Transportation (Ann Arbor and Washtenaw), 2002-2003 (Box 15)
    - Transportation, Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act, 1994 (Box 15)
    - University of Michigan Master Plan, 1999 (Box 15)
    - University of Michigan Sustainable Food System Project, 2001 (Box 15)
    - Urban Environment Alliance, 1997-2001; 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Washtenaw County Extension Advisory Council, 1993-1996 (Box 15)
    - Washtenaw County Reorganization, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Washtenaw Interfaith Network, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Washtenaw Libertarians, 1999 (Box 15)
    - Washtenaw County Toxics Project, 1989-1991 (Box 15)
    - Waste Imports, 1997-2004 (Box 15)
    - Waste Packaging Workgroup, 1989-1990 (Box 15)
    - Waste Reduction, 1990-1991 (Box 15)
    - Waste-Solid Waste User Fees (Ann Arbor), 1991 (Box 15)
    - Waste-Toronto Trash Problem, 1996 (Box 15)
    - Waste-Wayne County Solid Waste Plant, 1996-1999 (Box 15)
    - Willow Run Creek Site, 1994-1996 (Box 15)
    - Woodcreek Subdivision, 1995-1996 (Box 15)
    - YP3 (Ypsilanti Pollution Prevention Project), 1994-1996; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Ypsilanti Recycling, 1999 (Box 15)
  - 1972-2010, mainly 1988-2005
    The 1972-2010 subseries is exceptionally sizable and, among several topics, has three particularly strong subject areas. A large number of files focus on auto industry projects, the development of the GM PRISM project team, and efforts to reduce automotive toxic emissions. Another extensive section of this subseries contains the documents and files of councils and committees, various campaigns, and records of grants the Center has applied for. The grants are organized alphabetically according to granting organization. The third subject area includes environmental education materials, focusing largely on groundwater education, and the continuing efforts of Recycle Ann Arbor.
    - Auto Projects, 1989-2005
      - Air Pollution, 1990; 2000 (Box 20)
      - Amory Lovins, 1993-2001
        - Hypercars, 1998-2001 (Box 20)
        - Supercars/Rocky Mountain Institute, 1993-1995 (Box 20)
      - Citizens Automotive Pollution Prevention Alliance (CAPPA) Meetings, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
      - Climate Change Policy, 1998 (Box 20)
      - Community Environmental Awareness Project (CEAP), 1998-2001
        - Chrysler-Sterling Heights, 1998 (Box 20)
        - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 20)
        - Newsletters and Reports, 1999-2001
          - Community Environmental Awareness Project Newsletter, September 2001 (Box 20)
          - Community Environmental Awareness Project: General Motors Detroit/Hamtramck Assembly Center, 2001 (Box 20)
          - Community Environmental Awareness Project Newsletter, September 2000 (Box 20)
          - Community Environmental Awareness Project: Ford Motor Company Assembly Plant, 2000 (Box 20)
          - Community Environmental Awareness Project Newsletter, August 1999 (Box 20)
          - Community Environmental Awareness Project: DaimlerChrysler Sterling Heights Assembly Plant, 2000 (Box 20)
      - Critical Materials Register / Annual Wastewater Reporting, 1996-2000
        - Correspondence, 1996-2000 (Box 20)
        - INFORM -- Persistent and Bioaccumulative Toxins (PBTs) Great Lakes Study, 1997-1999 (Box 20)
      - Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ) -- Pollution Prevention Michigan Auto Project, 1991; 1999-2004
        - Reports, 2000; 2003-2004
          - Michigan Auto Project Progress Report, 2000 (Box 20)
          - Pollution Prevention: Making Sustainability a Reality, 2003 (Box 20)
        - Stakeholder Group Meetings and Correspondence, 1991; 1999-2001 (Box 20)
      - Environmental Vehicles Conference, 1998 (Box 20)
      - Fuel Efficiency, 1992-1996
        - The Mackinac, November 1992 (Box 20)
        - Partnership for a New Generation of Vehicles: Program Plan, 1994 (Box 20)
        - Technical Report: Light Duty Automotive Technology and Fuel Economy Trends Through 1996 (Box 20)
      - General Motors/Michigan DEQ Court Appeal, 2001-2002 (Box 20)
        (regarding air permit pollution controls)
      - General Motors Partnership for Regulatory Innovation and Sustainable Manufacturing (GM PRISM), 1994-1998
        - Case Study Illustration, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
        - Chemical Priorities, 1996-1997 (Box 20)
        - Community Outreach Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 20)
        - Environmental Management System (EMS), 1996-1997 (Box 20)
        - GM/Coalition for Environmentally Responsible Economics (CERES), 1994-1996 (Box 20)
        - GM Moraine Project, 1994-1997
          - Meetings and Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 20)
          - Ohio Prevention First Program, 1994-1996 (Box 20)
          - Work Plans and Project Designs, 1996-1997 (Box 20)
            (includes member lists)
        - Management Group, 1996-1997 (Box 20)
        - Meetings and Correspondence, 1996-1998
          - GM-Vehicle Manufacturing Pilot Project/PRISM, 1996-1997 (Box 20)
          - PRISM, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
          - Public Relations Team, 1996-1997 (Box 20)
        - Policy Group, 1996-1997 (Box 20)
        - Pollution Prevention (P2)/Environmental Management Workgroup, 1993-1997 (Box 20)
        - PRISM Final Report, 1996-1998
          - Baseline Environmental Requirements, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
          - Caucus Notes, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
          - Draft Materials, 1998 (Box 21)
          - Facility Profiles, 1996-1997 (Box 21)
          - Report Outline and Schedule, 1996-1997 (Box 21)
          - PRISM: An Alternative Regulatory System Model for Vehicle Manufacturing, 1997 (Box 21)
      - Great Lakes Automotive Pollution Prevention Alliance (GLAPPA), 1991-1997
        - Announcements, 1991 (Box 21)
        - Auto Article, 1994 (Box 21)
        - Auto Industry Data, 1991-1996 (Box 21)
        - Automotive Supplier Pollution Prevention Forum, 1991-1993 (Box 21)
        - Automotive Suppliers Project Research, 1992-1993 (Box 21)
        - Chicago Strategy Meeting, 1995-1996 (Box 21)
        - Conference Call Agendas, 1995 (Box 21)
        - Core Advisory Group, 1994 (Box 21)
        - Great Lakes Pollution Prevention Plan, 1991 (Box 21)
        - Mailings, 1995-1997 (Box 21)
        - Meetings, 1994 (Box 21)
      - Great Lakes National Program Office (GLNPO), 1993-1995 (Box 21)
      - Great Lakes Protection Fund, 1992-1995 (Box 21)
      - Great Lakes United (GLU), 1993 (Box 21)
      - Green Machines, 2002-2004 (Box 21)
      - Greenpeace Great Lakes Project, 1991-1992
        - The Product is the Poison Part II: Chlorinated Solvents and the Great Lakes Auto Industry, 1991 (Box 21)
        - Greenpeace Contract, 1992 (Box 21)
      - Management Institute for Environmental Business (MEB), 1993-1994 (Box 21)
      - Metals Fabrication Industry Sector Initiative, 1993-1994 (Box 21)
      - Motor Vehicle Manufacturers Association (MVMA) Presentation to the United Auto Workers (UAW), 1991-1992 (Box 21)
      - Proposal -- Energy and Environmental Technical Assistance Partnership, 1993 (Box 21)
      - Research, 1991-1995
        - Bob Ginsburg, 1992-1995
          - Auto Research, 1992-1994 (Box 21)
          - Chrysler Use Data, 1994 (Box 21)
          - Delphi VII Forecast and Analysis of the North American Automotive Industry, 1994 (Box 21)
          - Research Contracts, 1992-1995 (Box 21)
        - Canadian Agreement, 1991-1993 (Box 21)
        - Chrysler Corporation Pollution Prevention, 1992 (Box 21)
        - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Reports, 1991-1994 (Box 21)
        - Ford Motor Company, 1991-1992 (Box 21)
      - So Much Promise, So Little Progress, 1992-1994
        - Center for Clean Products and Clean Technologies at the University of Tennessee, 1994 (Box 21)
        - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 21)
        - Regulatory Barriers, 1991-1993 (Box 21)
        - So Much Promise, So Little Progress: An Evaluation of the State of Michigan/Auto Industry Great Lakes Pollution Prevention Initiative, 1993 (Box 21)
        - Toxics Reduction Project
          - 1992-1993 (Box 21)
          - 1993-1994 (Box 21)
          - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 21)
        - UAW Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 21)
        - United States Council for Automotive (US CAR) Research -- Press Releases, 1993 (Box 21)
      - Sustainable Plastics, 2005 (Box 21)
        (includes Moving Towards Sustainable Plastics: A Report Card on the Six Leading Automakers)
      - Toxics, 1989-2005
        - Auto Industry Pollution Prevention Project (Auto Project), 1991-1993 (Box 21)
        - Auto Initiative -- Great Lakes System Persistent Toxics List, 1991 (Box 21)
        - Automotive Lead Use, 2003-2005 (Box 21)
        - Clean Steel Network, 1991-1992 (Box 22)
        - Council on Environmental Quality (CEQ), 1989-1990 (Box 22)
          (includes the 1990 State of the Environment Report)
        - Gage Products, 1989-1994 (Box 22)
        - National Toxics Campaign, 1992-1993 (Box 22)
          (includes The National Toxics Campaign: Some Reflections, Thoughts for the Movement)
        - Press Releases, 1991-1994 (Box 22)
        - Right-To-Act (RTA) Campaign, 1991-1993 (Box 22)
        - Toxics in Vehicles: Mercury, 2001 (Box 22)
        - UAW -- NSK Corporation Worksite Inspection, 1989 (Box 22)
      - United States Auto Project Advisory Group (APAG), 1991-2001; 2004
        - American Automobile Manufacturers Association (AAMA)-Auto Pollution Prevention Case Studies, 1996-1998 (Box 22)
        - Final Progress Report: US Automotive Pollution Prevention Project, 1998 (Box 22)
        - Materials Group, 1994-1996 (Box 22)
        - Meetings and Correspondence
          - 1992-1994 (Box 22)
          - 1995 (Box 22)
          - 1996-1997 (Box 22)
          - 1997-1998 (Box 22)
        - Report Draft Materials, 1997 (Box 22)
        - Suppliers, 1996 (Box 22)
    - Bottle Bill, 2000-2008 (Box 22)
    - Councils and Committees, 1985-2006
      - Ann Arbor Public Schools (AAPS) Environmental Advisory Committee, 1985; 1988-2002 (Box 22)
        (2 folders)
      - Beldon, 2000; 2004-2005
        - ECCO Field Plan for Detroit -- Beldon Key States Program, 2004-2005 (Box 22)
        - Michigan Joint Project, 2000 (Box 22)
      - Groundwater Remediation Committee, 1989-1997 (Box 22)
      - Michigan Environmental Council (MEC), 2004-2006
        - Meetings and Reports, 2004-2006 (Box 22)
          (includes the 2004 Michigan Environmental Council 2004 Annual Report)
        - MEC / Ecology Center Science Advisory Committee, 2000-2002 (Box 22)
          (includes Guarding Michigan's Most Vulnerable: Making Michigan a Leader in Protecting Children from Environmental Pollution)
      - Michigan Environmental Health Coalition, 1995-1998 (Box 22)
      - Rebecca Kanner, 1987-2002
        (Director of Environmental Education for the Ecology Center of Ann Arbor)
        - Environmental Education Network of Washtenaw Directory, 2000 (Box 23)
        - GEE-WOW! Planning, 2000 (Box 23)
        - Gelman Sciences, 1993-1994 (Box 23)
        - Internal Management and Procedures (IMP), 1989-1994
          - Financial Reports, 1992-1994 (Box 23)
          - Meetings and Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 23)
        - Strategic Planning for the Ecology Center
          - 1987 (Box 23)
          - 1988 (Box 23)
          - 1989 (Box 23)
          - 1990 (Box 23)
          - 1991 (Box 23)
          - 1994 (Box 23)
          - 1996 (Box 23)
        - Washtenaw County / Michigan State University Extension, 1998-2002
          - Consumer Agricultural Committee, 1998-2000 (Box 23)
          - Washtenaw County Extension Advisory Council, 2001-2002 (Box 23)
      - Recycling Organics Team (ROT), 1995-1997 (Box 23)
        (formerly Master Composters Roundtable)
      - Solid Waste Environmental Action Team (SWEAT), 1988 (Box 23)
      - Washtenaw County Local Emergency Planning Committee (LEPC), 1987-1999
        - Accident Prevention Legislation, 1987-1992 (Box 23)
        - Clean Air Act / Chemical Accident Prevention, 1994 (Box 23)
        - Ecology Center of Ann Arbor vs. Johnson Controls, Inc. Court Case, 1993 (Box 23)
        - EPA Risk Management Plan / Working Group on Community Right-to-Know, 1993-1997 (Box 23)
        - Meetings and Correspondence, 1995-1999 (Box 23)
          (includes LEPC Bulletin for April 1995 and Winter 1996)
        - Michigan State Police Emergency Management Division Review, 1992 (Box 23)
        - SARA Title III, 1990; 1993-1995 (Box 23)
        - Sarns/3M Health Care, 1993 (Box 23)
          (includes Welcome to Sarnes/3M Healthcare -- Annex G Fire Service to the Washtenaw County Emergency Operations Plan)
        - TRI Washtenaw County Project, 1990 (Box 23)
        - Washtenaw County Toxics, 1990-1995 (Box 23)
      - Washtenaw County Solid Waste Consortium (WCCSWM) Home Composting Task Force, 1994-1998 (Box 23)
    - Don't Trash Michigan, 1988; 1997-2004
      - Campaign
        - 2000-2003, 2 folders (Box 23)
          (includes Everyone's Backyard, Vol. 17, No.3, Fall 1999 and the 1998 Michigan Solid Waste Policy)
        - 2003-2004 (Box 23)
      - Trash Bills, 1997-1998; 2003 (Box 23)
    - Environmental Education, 1988-2005
      - 50 Simple Things Game Show and Environmental Skits (Box 23)
      - Curriculum Masters
        - Fuel for Thought: A high school activity and resource guide teaching about transportation and alternative fuels, 1998 (Box 23)
        - GEE-WOW! Adventures in Water Education: An Exciting K-6 Curriculum about Water and Groundwater!, 1996 (Box 23)
      - Earth Art and Poetry: A Coloring and Poetry Book About Our Earth (Box 23)
      - Earth Day 1990 Lesson Plan and Home Survey -- K-6 and 7-12, 1990 (Box 23)
      - Environmental Explorations, 1997
        - Environmental Explorations: A Fun, Hands-On Curriculum! (Project-based science for upper elementary school students), 1996 (Box 24)
        - Livingston and Washtenaw Mathematics and Science Center, 1995-1996 (Box 24)
        - Ruth Kraut: Miscellaneous, 1990-2004 (Box 24)
          (scattered)
        - Turtles & Co.: The Wetlands Story (Activities for Grades K-8) (Box 24)
        - Urban Environmental Education Project, 1997 (Box 24)
      - Environmental Learning Fund, 1997-1998 (Box 24)
      - GO! Outdoors Program, 2003-2005 (Box 24)
      - Great Lakes Assembly (Box 24)
        (includes themed plays for grades K-2)
      - Great Lakes Environmental Education Project, circa, 1994 (Box 24)
      - Groundwater, 1984-1997
        - Activities (Box 24)
          (includes Bucket Brigade and Dripial Pursuit)
        - Flow Models and Worksheets (Box 24)
        - GEE-WOW! Adventures in Water Education: An Exciting K-6 Curriculum about Water and Groundwater!, 1996 (Box 24)
        - Groundwater Education in Michigan (GEM) Workshop, circa 1990 (Box 24)
        - Groundwater Education on Wheels: Programs and Displays in Groundwater Education and Environmental Awareness for Students (A Request for Funding), 1988 (Box 24)
          (includes Fall 1998 Nonprofit Energy News; December 1988 Ecology Reports; and 1987 Ecology Center Ann Arbor, Inc. Annual Report)
        - Groundwater Festival, 1989; 1994-1997
          - Is Dilution the Solution to Pollution?, 1996 (Box 24)
          - So You're Thinking About a Groundwater Festival..., 1997 (Box 24)
          - Fact Sheets and Worksheets, 1989 (Box 24)
          - How Does Water Move Through Earth Materials?, 1996 (Box 24)
          - Recipes for Clean Groundwater, 1994 (Box 24)
          - Water Treatment Exercise (Box 24)
        - Watershed Suite: Supplemental Science Activities to Accompany John Wunsch's Watershed Suite (Box 24)
        - Visual Materials
          - Poster: Groundwater and Land Use in the Water Cycle, 1984 (Box 24)
          - Slides (Box 24)
      - Household Hazardous Materials: Games and Worksheets for Grades 4-6 (Box 24)
      - Land Use Game, 1999
        - Modified (Box 24)
        - Original, 1999 (Box 24)
      - Mercury Activities and Information, 2000 (Box 24)
      - Old Ecology Center Environmental Education Programs (Box 24)
        (includes What's Hands-On, Fun, and Helps Save the Earth? Environmental Education from the Ecology Center! brochure)
      - Outdoor Education Activities for Preschoolers, 1989 (Box 24)
      - Pollution Solutions (Box 24)
        (a.k.a. Pollution Prevention and You)
      - Recycling Curricula, 2003 (Box 24)
      - Recycling Curriculum: Activities for Preschool through Senior High, 1984 (Box 24)
      - Recycling Education Program, 1992; 1997-1998
        - Activities and Informational Materials, 1992; 1997-1998 (Box 24)
        - Taking Action in Recycling: Learning from Nature, Applying to our Communities, 1997-1998 (Box 24)
          (includes EPA Grant materials)
        - TrashCan Gazette (Box 24)
      - Recycling and Education Station, 1989-1991
        - Plan and Contracts, 1990-1991 (Box 24)
        - Station Development, 1988-1991; 2 folders (Box 24)
        - Textbook and Volunteer Materials, 1991 (Box 24)
          (includes The Recycling and Education Station Getting Ready Activities)
      - Smart Movin' Program, 1998-2001
        - Correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 25)
        - Fuel for Thought: A high school activity and resource guide teaching about transportation and alternative fuels, 1998 (Box 25)
        - Miscellaneous Publications, 2000 (Box 25)
          (includes Winter 2000 Ann Arbor Area Clean Cities/The Waste Watchers in... The Mystery of the Unsmelly Bus! and Spring/Summer 2000 Waste Watcher)
      - Solid Waste Education Program: Lesson Plans for All Programs, 1992-1993 (Box 25)
      - Toxics In My Home? You Bet!: Curriculum on Household Toxics for Grades 7-8, 1985 (Box 25)
      - University of Michigan Children's Hospital Asthma Unit -- Environmental Detectives: A Curriculum for 2nd through 5th Grades (Box 25)
        (includes Environmental Detectives: Handouts)
    - Events, 1990-2007
      - Aveda Earth Month, 2000-2003 (Box 25)
      - Earth Day
        - 1990 (Box 25)
        - 2004 (Box 25)
      - Ecology Center 30th Anniversary, 2000 (Box 25)
      - Ecology Center Planning Retreat, 2001 (Box 25)
      - Energy Program/Event with Energy Expert: Dr. Herman Scheer, 2007 (Box 25)
      - Jackson Groundwater Festival, 1993 (Box 25)
      - Miscellaneous, 2000-2003 (Box 25)
        (includes special event letters and promotional material)
      - Open Space Zoning Workshop, 2001 (Box 25)
      - Race & Environment Conference, 1990 (Box 25)
      - Regional Planning Invitations, 2002 (Box 25)
    - Grants, 1972-1973; 1987-2002
      - Ann Arbor Area Community Foundation, 1987; 1990-2000
        - Directory of Environmental Education Programs Project, 1999-2000 (Box 25)
        - Environmental Leadership Training for High School Students from Public and Subsidized Housing, 1993-1995 (Box 25)
        - Footloose in Washtenaw, 1987 (Box 25)
        - GEE-WOW! Program, 1990-1991 (Box 25)
        - Miscellaneous Project Grants, 1990-1992 (Box 25)
        - Rebycicle Program, 1997 (Box 25)
        - Smart Movin': Teaching Youth to Green Commute, 2000 (Box 25)
        - Wetlands and Water Quality Programs, 1991-1993 (Box 25)
      - Ann Arbor Energy Fund, 1999 (Box 25)
        (for the Smart Movin' Program)
      - Bauman Family Foundation, 1989 (Box 25)
        (for SARA Title III and Right-to-Know efforts)
      - Community Foundation of Southeastern Michigan, 1988 (Box 25)
        (Non-Profit Energy Conservation Program Proposal for the Energy Conservation Education and Training Program)
      - E. Carlson Trust, 1988-1989 (Box 25)
        (for training in areas of toxic substances)
      - Green Backs for Green Acts, 1994-1995 (Box 25)
        (for The Home Composting Project, An Educational and Pilot Program for Washtenaw County)
      - Jenifer Altman Foundation, 1997 (Box 25)
        (for work on the national Health Care Without Harm Campaign)
      - Joyce Foundation, 1989-1996
        - Auto Industry Pollution Prevention Project, 1989-1996 (Box 25)
        - Fertile Ground: A Sustainable Agriculture Project for Michigan Growers, 1989 (Box 25)
        - Toxic Source Reduction, 1991 (Box 25)
      - Junior League of Ann Arbor, 1988-1990; 1996-2000
        - Environmental Education Curriculum, 1996 (Box 25)
        - GEE-WOW! Program, 1990; 2000 (Box 25)
          (includes 1988 IRS tax exemption request)
        - ReBicycle Project, 1998 (Box 25)
      - Kiwanis Club of Ann Arbor, 1972-2000
        - Miscellaneous Assistance Letters, 1972-1988 (Box 25)
        - ReBicycle Project, 2000 (Box 25)
      - Michigan Department of Commerce -- Michigan Equity Program, 1988-1990 (Box 25)
        (for The GEE-WOW! Ecology Van: Environmental Education Outreach Program)
      - Michigan Department of Consumer & Industry Services -- Community Energy Efficiency Project, 1998-2002 (Box 25)
        (for Smart Movin': Bike, Bus, or Walk to School Program)
      - National Environmental Education and Training Foundation, 1995-1997 (Box 25)
        (for the Great Lakes Pollution Prevention Project)
      - The Philanthropic Collaborative, Inc., 1997-1998 (Box 25)
        (for the Without Harm Campaign)
      - Rosebud Foundation, 2000-2001 (Box 25)
        (for the Smart Movin': Bike, Bus, or Walk to School Program)
      - Rotary Club of Ann Arbor, 2002 (Box 25)
        (for the Environmental Education Network of Washtenaw (EE NOW))
      - Ruth Mott Fund, 1994-1995
        - Citizen Action for Pollution Prevention Project, 1994 (Box 25)
        - The Environmental Connection: The Rising Rates of Breast Cancer, Reproductive Disorders and Children's Disease, 1995 (Box 25)
      - Sage Foundation, 1989 (Box 25)
        (for ECO-HELP: Environmental Information and Referral Service for Southeast and Southern Michigan)
      - Solid Waste Department, 1995; 1998-2001 (Box 25)
        (Contract Renewal for the Solid Waste Youth Educational Services)
      - United States Environmental Protection Agency, 1992-2001
        - Building Success: An Environmental Leadership Training Program for High School Students from Public and Subsidized Housing, 1992-1995 (Box 25)
        - Education for Environmental Justice, 1994-1997 (Box 25)
        - Kids Can Make a Difference, 1998-2001 (Box 25)